<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>3 | Maximilian Matthe</title><link>/publication-type/3/</link><atom:link href="/publication-type/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>3</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/media/icon_hu1f2f04da04b535428ef66c1a6d7baa41_8019_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>3</title><link>/publication-type/3/</link></image><item><title>Parties as Brands: Linking Positioning Dynamics to Voter Support</title><link>/work_in_progress/political-mapping/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/work_in_progress/political-mapping/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3></description></item><item><title>Politics in Flux: Dynamic Party Positioning and Voter Support</title><link>/workingpaper/political-mapping/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workingpaper/political-mapping/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3></description></item><item><title>Identifying Consumers’ Information Needs in Online Search</title><link>/workingpaper/online-search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workingpaper/online-search/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Consumers routinely use online search engines, such as Google, to search for information. In response, many firms provide such information to attract consumers during their online searches. Thereby, a prerequisite for successfully attracting a firm’s target audience is identifying what information these consumers desire. To do so, firms must understand consumers’ information needs, that is, the information consumers seek to obtain with their searches. Yet, identifying information needs is non-trivial, as information needs naturally are (I) unobservable and (II) heterogeneous across consumers. This article aims to provide an approach for identifying consumers’ information needs within their online searches. To do so, we develop a novel market research approach and validate it in an empirical application. Our approach enables researchers and firms to collect primary data at scale in a real-time online search environment, and identify consumer information needs through unstructured data analysis. We implement our approach for online searches around “credit cards” in Germany. Our approach reveals nine broad information needs, including information around prices and fees, specific brands, traveling, or mobile payment options. Moreover, our analysis shows that information needs differ across consumers, for instance, across genders and along the purchase funnel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Estimating Positioning Dynamics in Parliamentary Speeches</title><link>/_unused_right_now/political-mapping/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/_unused_right_now/political-mapping/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
Click the &lt;em>Cite&lt;/em> button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em>Slides&lt;/em> button to check out the example.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">code, math, and images&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privacy Regulation and Competition Dynamics in the Tracking Industry</title><link>/work_in_progress/tracker-mapping/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/work_in_progress/tracker-mapping/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3></description></item></channel></rss>